On December 4th, 1926, Agatha Christie, the world's most famous mystery writer, disappeared. What may have
happened during the next eleven days is far more suspenseful than anything she ever wrote.
Agatha is a drama, mystery, thriller film directed by Michael Apted.
England, 1926.
An American journalist looks for mystery writer Agatha Christie when she
suddenly disappears without explanation, leaving no trace.
Wally Stanton, played by Dustin Hoffman.
Agatha Christie, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Archie Christie, played by Timothy Dalton.
Evelyn, played by Helen Morse.
Nancy Neele, played by Celia Gregory.
John Foster, played by Paul Brooke.
Agatha is a 1979 British drama thriller film directed by Michael Apted and
starring Vanessa Redgrave, Dustin Hoffman and Timothy Dalton.
It was written by Kathleen Tynan.
The film focuses on renowned crime writer Agatha
Christie's famous 11-day disappearance in 1926.
The film was released 9 February 1979, receiving generally positive reviews
from critics, who praised the production values and performances.
At the 52nd Academy Awards for films from 1979, it received a
nomination for Best Costume Design for Shirley Russell.
The award, however, went to Albert Wolsky for All That Jazz.
The film explores themes of journalist, husband wife
relationship, england, historical figure, disappearance.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.